<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project-plan.xsl"?>
<plan plan-format="1.0" xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="Xtext">
  <release projectid="modeling.tmf.xtext" version="2.1.0"/>
  <introduction>
    <html:div>
      <html:p>
     This document lays out the feature and API set for the Indigo version of the Xtext (version 2.1.0).  
      </html:p>
    </html:div>
  </introduction>
  <release_deliverables>
    <html:div>
The release deliverables have the same form as is found in most Eclipse projects, namely:
      <html:p>
        <html:ul>
         <html:li>Xtext SDK (includes runtime and tooling components, with sources, examples, and documentation) (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
		 <html:li>Xtext runtime binary distribution (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
		 <html:li>Xtext tests (downloadable and update site)</html:li>
         <html:li>Xbase SDK (includes a reusable expression langauge implemented in Xtext, with sources, examples, and documentation) (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
		 <html:li>Xbase runtime binary distribution (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
		 <html:li>Xbase tests (downloadable and update site)</html:li>
         <html:li>Xtend2 SDK (a domein-specific language for customizing all aspects of Xtext. Built with Xtext and based on Xbase. Includes runtime and tooling components, with sources, examples, and documentation) (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
		 <html:li>Xtend2 runtime binary distribution (downloadable and update site).</html:li>
		 <html:li>Xtend2 tests (downloadable and update site)</html:li>
        </html:ul>
      </html:p>
    </html:div>
  </release_deliverables>
  <release_milestones>
      <milestone date="11/02/2011" milestone="2.1.0 Final"></milestone>
  </release_milestones>
  <target_environments>
    <html:div>
In order to remain current, each Eclipse release targets reasonably current versions of the underlying operating environments.
The Xtext project depends upon on the 3.5 (Galileo) release of the Eclipse Platform and other projects, and targets to run on 
version 1.5 of the Java Runtime Environment, Standard Edition. 
    </html:div>
  </target_environments>
  <compatibility_with_previous_releases>
    <html:div>
Version 2.1 will be binary compatible with languages build with Xtext version 2.0. However several provisional APIs have been changed.
    </html:div>
  </compatibility_with_previous_releases>
  <themes_and_priorities>
    <preamble>
      <html:div>
A list of project requirements and agreed upon implementation time frames is 
found in this document. For the milestones listed in this document, a set of 
overall themes is used to indicate what major set of functionalities is to be 
concentrated on for each. These themes are presented below, while the 
requirements document and associated Bugzilla entries are left to those wanting 
more detailed information on each.
      </html:div>
    </preamble>
    <theme name="Reusability">
    <description>
        <html:div>
          Xbase is a sophisticated language library, providing the power of full-blown expressions to any
          Xtext-based language targeting the Java platform.
          Xtext eats its own dog-food and comes with a new compiler language called Xtend2, which is itself implmentd in Xtext
          and based on Xbase.
        </html:div>
    </description>
    </theme>
    <theme name="Increase Applicability">
      <description>
        <html:div>
          One of our guiding principles is "make common things easier and rare things possible" suggests that we focus on extensibility as well as
          on simplicity with regards to all kinds of API. In Helios we want to allow Xtext to be used in more situations by providing an easy to reuse base language. 
        </html:div>
      </description>
    </theme>
    <theme name="Performance and Scalability">
    <description>
        <html:div>
          Performance and scalability needs to be further enforced.
        </html:div>
    </description>
    </theme>
    <theme name="Clean Code">
      <description>
        <html:div>
          Keeping the quality of code high is key for long lasting software systems.
          We want to further keep our code clean, which means doing things like removing dead code, cleaning up / rewriting code we do no longer understand, 
          avoiding redundancy, etc..
        </html:div>
    </description>
    </theme>
    <theme name="Eclipse 4.1">
      <description>
        <html:div>
          We do not explicitly test against 4.1.
        </html:div>
    </description>
    </theme>
  </themes_and_priorities>
  <appendix name="Legal Notices">
    <html:div>
      <html:ul>
        <html:li>Java is a trademark or a registered trademark of Sun Microsystems, Inc.</html:li>
        <html:li>All other products or company names are mentioned for identification purposes only, and may be trademarks or service marks of their respective owners.</html:li>
      </html:ul>
    </html:div>
  </appendix>
</plan>
